Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
NARRATOR: Long ago. a mythic
battle between good and evil
played out in ancient China:
The country was torn by civil war.
with many kingdoms
struggling for land and power:
But one king had a ruthless ambition
to make himself emperor by the sword:
(CLEARING THROAT)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Leave me.
Prepare for war!
NARRATOR: The other rulers hired assassins
to kill the King
before he could conquer them all:
(GRUNTING)
(SWORDS CLASHING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Stop! I am not harmed.
We attack tonight!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
NARRATOR: Kingdom by kingdom.
his army swept away everything in its path.
and anyone who resisted met a terrible fate:
The country was his:
He was now Emperor of All Under Heaven:
He enslaved his conquered enemies
and forced them to build his Great Wall:
When they were dead or useless.
he had them buried beneath it:
The Emperor's mystics taught him
mastery over the five elements.
fire. water. earth. wood and metal:
His power seemed without limit:
He was master of millions.
but like the lowliest peasant.
he could not stop growing old:
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
I have too much to do for one lifetime.
NARRATOR: He needed to defeat
his last enemy. death itself:
One day. news came of a powerful witch
who was rumoured to know
the secret to eternal life:
He ordered General Ming. his oldest friend
and trusted ally. to find her:
The witch was named Zi Yuan.
and she was nothing
like the General expected:
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Your Majesty...
Rise up.
I do not possess the secret of
immortality. my Lord...
...but I know where to find it.
General...
No man is to touch her.
She is mine.
NARRATOR: On the western border
stood the Monastery of Turfan:
There was housed the greatest library
in the ancient world.
and Zi Yuan was sure
the secret to eternal life was here:
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
This is a key.
NARRATOR: It was the long lost
oracle bones.
a collection of all the mystical secrets
of the ancient world:
The Emperor's answer was here
along with other magic beyond imagining:
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
You have served me well.
I will grant you anything you desire.
I want to spend my life with General Ming.
Of course.
Read.
(CHANTING IN SANSKRIT)
NARRATOR: She cast the spell in Sanskrit.
an ancient language
that the Emperor did not understand:
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
I feel your spell working.
I am now immortal.
Come. I want to show you something.
(EXCLAIMING)
Become my queen and I will let him live.
Do what he says! Save yourself!
You will never keep your word.
You are right.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
Now. join General Ming in hell.
(SHOUTING)
What did you do to me?
I cursed you and your army.
(EMPEROR GRUNTING IN PAIN)
Surround the Palace!
The Emperor is in trouble!
NARRATOR: The curse must never be lifted.
or the Emperor will rise again
to enslave all of mankind:
On that dark day.
there will be nothing and no one to save us:
You can run. but you can't hide.
One o'clock.
OXFORDSHIRE. ENGLAND
Ten o'clock. one o'clock. Ten o'clock. one...
And this is something for grown men to do?
(EXCLAIMING IN PAIN)
(GRUNTING) Come on.
(SCREAMS)
Bite on this.
Evy. I'm home!
Mrs O'Connell is at her book reading. sir.
She'll be home for dinner.
Oh. right. Well. that's great.
'cause we're having fish.
You didn't think I'd catch anything.
did you?
I had the utmost confidence. sir.
JAMESON: There's a hook in your neck. sir.
Shall I fetch the wire cutters?
RICK: Fall back! Follow me!
Move! Move! Move! Move!
EVELYN: "Now safely aboard the airship
with the mummy finally vanquished.
LONDON
"Dash swept Scarlet into his arms:
"'Oh. God. Scarlet. I thought I'd lost you.'
'For a moment there. you did.'
"Bathed in rays of golden sunlight.
"our heroes sealed their reunion
with a kiss of timeless passion.
"their love deeper and truer than ever."
Mrs O'Connell. we're all dying to know.
is the Scarlet O'Keefe character
really based on you?
Honestly. I can say
she's a completely different person.
- Any more questions?
- WOMAN: Mrs O'Connell...
Mrs O'Connell. is your life today
as exciting as it was before the war?
(SIGHS)
I wish my life were that exciting now.
MAN: Will there be another book
in the series?
WOMAN 2: Do you believe in happy endings?
(EXHALES)
Isn't this blissful?
Dinner at home.
- Every night.
- Here's to retirement.
- May we stay this happy forever.
(GULPS)
Still no letter from Alex.
I've sent him three in the last month.
Yeah. well. what do you expect?
The only time we ever hear from that kid
is when he's getting kicked out of college
or he needs more money.
I'm sure he's just buried in his studies.
- So. how did your book reading go?
- Oh. fine. Thank you.
Until they asked me. "When will there
be another Mummy adventure?"
Yeah. but you did promise the publisher
a third book.
I know.
But I spend my nights staring
at a blank page. completely blocked.
We could skip dinner. and I could
attempt to inspire you upstairs.
Oh. that's so sweet of you. darling.
But I'm going to sit at that typewriter
until something exciting comes out.
Thank you.
(EXCLAIMING DELIGHTEDLY)
Trout. How lovely!
(JAMESON CLEARS THROAT)
I'm so happy you found a hobby
that doesn't involve guns.
(CRUNCHING)
NINGXIA PROVINCE. CHINA
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Don't worry. we'll find the entrance today.
Li Tung. what's for lunch?
Noodle soup.
Very good.
ALEX: Good. Wilson's back.
You're a couple days late. Professor.
I was beginning to think
you'd run into bandits.
Oh. my dear fellow.
thank you for the concern.
- Are you thirsty?
- Oh. yes. please.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
You know.
when I saw you standing up there.
I thought I was looking at your father.
You really are Rick O'Connell's son.
Yeah. well. hopefully after today.
he'll be known as Alex O'Connell's father.
What a powerful face!
When I told my colleagues at the museum
that you had discovered the Colossus.
they were thrilled.
- Yes. however...
- I know.
When am I gonna get in that tomb?
Don't let the buggers get you down.
It was you that discovered
the Bembridge journal.
and with it. you'll discover the Emperor.
- I have complete faith in you. Alex.
- Thank you. Professor.
Thanks for believing in me.
(MAN SHOUTS)
We found it! We found the door!
Bad Mummy:
Yeah.
Vile Mummy?
(TYPING)
No. Cursed Mummy!
Mysterious Mummy:
Malignant Mummy:
Prepare to die!
Take that!
Rick!
Darling. where are you?
I'm ready to be inspired.
Do you remember the time
the mummy had me tied down?
And you came to save me and you cut...
No! You tore open the ropes
is what you did.
just as he was about to plunge his...
(SNORING)
Oh. rats.
(LAUGHS)
Watch out!
- Emperor didn't want any houseguests.
- Yeah.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Stay together.
Sir Colin Bembridge.
Oh. gee...
He went searching for this tomb
70 years ago.
They left him like this as a warning.
Unfortunately. this is not the dead man
that's gonna make us famous.
Let's keep moving.
Look at it. Alex.
Look at it!
(SCREAMING)
Chu Wah!
(WHIMPERING)
(SHOUTS IN MANDARIN)
(PANTING)
- Chu Wah.
- No. no. don't. don't. don't.
Alex. Alex. they're dead! Come on.
This kind of danger goes with the territory.
You know that better than anyone.
Alex!
- Yes?
- Okay.
- Yeah.
All right. good chap. Okay. Good chap.
Oh. Jesus.
All the warriors are facing in to this point.
- as if awaiting an order from the Emperor.
- Well. then. where is he?
Listen. you don't think some bloody grave
robber's beaten us to the prize. do you?
No. he's still here.
You see. this is a feng shui compass.
Okay. Now. This...
Okay. this is true north.
but the feng shui compass
is set in the opposite direction.
- All right. we need to realign it.
- All right.
- All right. here we go.
(ALEX SCREAMS)
(RAT SQUEAKING)
Alex! Alex. speak to me!
Are you all right?
- Alex!
- I'm fine.
Tell me. have we found the Emperor?
Alex!
What is it?
It's only the greatest find since King Tut!
"If he is awakened.
all mortals should despair."
It's definitely him!
(ALEX EXCLAIMS)
Even had his concubines buried alive
with him.
Selfish bastard.
Hey. Professor Wilson.
you want to come down and take a look?
Or are you so overwhelmed you can't talk?
(THUD)
(GRUNTING)
Wilson!
(PANTING)
Let's go. Professor.
We've got a lot of work to do.
WILSON: All right.
FRY: First of all. I'd just like to say
that the Foreign Office appreciates
all that you did during the war.
But I've been sent to offer you
one last assignment.
I'm afraid we've retired
from the espionage game. haven't we. dear?
Yeah. we've... We don't do that any more.
We're finished.
- EVELYN: Not at all.
- Completely done.
But just out of curiosity.
what is the mission anyway?
We need you to courier this to Shanghai.
(EVELYN GASPS)
- Nice piece of ice.
- It's the Eye of Shangri-La.
If you believe the legend.
it points the way to the Pool of Eternal Life.
It was smuggled out of China in 1940.
Now. the government would like
to return it to the Shanghai Museum
as a sign of good faith
to the Chinese people.
And with your expertise in the field.
we naturally thought of you.
Oh. we'd be so flattered.
But Rick and I. we made a promise
to each other after the war
that we would settle down.
- That's right. yeah. we did. didn't we? We...
- I see.
Well. I must admit I am a little disappointed.
Postwar China is very dangerous.
There are a lot of factions that would love
to get their hands on the Eye of Shangri-La.
In lesser hands.
the Eye could be lost forever.
We couldn't let that happen. could we?
No. that could be bad for the world.
- The world... Terrible.
- Yeah.
You know. she has a brother
who lives in Shanghai.
- Jonathan!
- Yes.
He owns a nightclub. if I'm not mistaken.
We have been meaning to visit. We could...
- We should...
...drop in and surprise him.
- Say hello.
- Why not?
Does this mean
we can count on you one last time?
Yes.
SHANGHAI. CHINA
CHINESE NEW YEAR. 1947
(CAR HONKING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
There we are.
Here's to you. Princess.
And lmhotep.
May the bugger actually stay dead.
(TOASTING IN RUSSIAN)
Ding-dong.
Hi. can you buy a drink for me?
Excuse me. Alex! Alex! You're back again.
Come here. Alex. Let me get you a drink.
Smooth special for the pup. huh?
The explorer.
(LAUGHS)
Make that two.
Sorry. Uncle Jon. but I got a better offer.
JONATHAN: No. no. Alex. No. look.
Listen. how can I... Come here.
To put it in archaeological terms.
that's a tomb
in which many pharaohs have lain.
Now. listen. listen.
just think about me for a moment. all right?
Your discovery will go public in a few days.
and your parents are sure to find out.
They're not gonna be happy
you've dropped out of school. And...
Will you relax. Uncle Jon? Okay? I'm here.
They're a long way away.
- Alex...
- Excuse me. okay?
I have some excavation to do.
Jonathan!
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
You're in China! Evy. Rick.
(STUTTERING) What are you... It's so...
I didn't even...
Brother. how lovely to see you.
I had no idea he was here!
- Who was here?
- Who?
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
MAN: This happens every time!
Every man in the bar!
- Dad?
- Alex!
MAN: I don't know what to do with you!
WOMAN: He's just a boy!
- I can't leave the room for 10 minutes!
- I didn't... Go away! Go to hell!
- MAN: I'm sick of it!
- Let's go get lover-boy!
I'm gonna kill you. kid!
Not so fast. that's my kid.
- Mad Dog Maguire?
- Ricochet O'Connell.
- Hey. hey.
- EVELYN: What are you doing here?
- Alex! Sweetheart! Are you all right?
- Just a little family get-together. folks.
Come on.
let's get back to having a good time. Music!
How long has it been?
Egypt. '23. French Foreign Legion.
This guy could land a plane
on anything. you...
- Why are you here?
- Ricochet. he had his hands all over me girl.
Now. son or no son.
I gotta give him a beating!
- Get out of the way. Dad.
- Sit down.
Now as much as I'd really like you
to teach him a valuable lesson...
His mother would be upset! Very upset.
You have a lot of explaining to do.
young man.
I got a wife now. and a kid.
Things are a little bit different.
I'm sure you understand.
- Yeah.
- Let me make it up to you.
We're just surprised to see you here.
That's all.
JONATHAN: Who's gonna pay
for all this damage?
All right?
I'm not here five minutes.
and I'm already pulling your fanny
out of the fire.
You're going back to college.
How'd you think this was gonna work. Dad?
You two show up. tell me what to do?
No. But we should sit down
and discuss this like a family.
No offence. Mom.
but we haven't been a family in a long time.
Hey. don't you turn your back on me. Alex!
Alex. just... Alex. come here.
Can you...
Don't look at me like that.
(SIGHS)
- It's all your fault!
- My fault?
You're the one
that's always smothering him.
You couldn't leave him alone
for five minutes without wiping his nose.
Perhaps I was overcompensating for the fact
that you never took an interest in his life.
His life was my top priority.
How many times did I save that kid
from breaking his neck?
A little warmth and encouragement
would have been nice.
I'm his father. It's implied.
We've spent our entire lives
searching for priceless artefacts.
and the one thing
that's most precious to us.
we've lost.
We can't let Alex become some stranger
in pictures on our mantle.
- We can't let that happen.
- No. we can't.
How are we gonna fix this?
We need to do it together.
PARAMILITARY OUTPOST
WESTERN CHINA
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
The O'Connells are in Shanghai.
Do they have the Eye of Shangri-La?
Our spy says they do.
Good.
Assemble the troops!
Yes sir.
Soldiers!
Soon all our training and sacrifice...
will bear great fruit.
It is my dream to raise our Emperor
from his tomb.
Only He can bring order out of this chaos.
Soldiers...
tonight our great battle begins!
(ALL CHANTING)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
You know. this might have been faster
if we took a rickshaw.
It's Chinese New Year.
Don't you just love this country?
They have so many extra little holidays.
and drinking is mandatory.
I can't believe
we get to see your first big discovery.
It's so exciting.
Well. after last night.
I'm surprised you want to see it at all.
JONATHAN: Listen.
I'll pick you up in about an hour.
EVELYN: You're not coming?
JONATHAN: No. no.
I've seen enough mummies to last a lifetime.
There he is.
Oh. my darling. very impressive.
When do you get to open the sarcophagus?
ALEX: Well.
after the official red tape has been cut.
Do the words "rest in peace"
mean anything to you two?
So. Mom. why don't you stick around
for the next few days.
and we can open it together?
I would like that very much. thanks.
Alex. why don't you go
and tell Professor Wilson
that we're here. You know...
No problem. Great.
Just don't wake the big guy up
while I'm gone.
Hey. Alex.
You know. this is all really. really big stuff.
Whatever you say. Dad.
(WHISTLING)
What?
You just have a certain glow about you
this evening I haven't seen in a long time.
I guess mummies bring out the best in me.
Take a wrong turn at Cairo?
Sorry to interrupt.
- Roger.
- Professor Roger Wilson.
Rick.
You know. when Alex told me
that you had gone legit.
I just couldn't believe my ears.
Well. now I just pillage tombs
in the name of preservation. Evelyn.
- Congratulations on your latest discovery.
- Alex deserves all the credit.
He's one hell of a kid.
He's like the son I never had.
And he's the only one we've got.
so the next time you send him
on one of your field trips.
you give us the heads-up first.
Yes. yes. of course.
And now. I believe you have
something that belongs to us.
What's that?
Oh. you mean this?
(GASPS)
(LAUGHING)
I'm sorry...
There. go ahead.
All yours. Rog.
I knew I could rely on you two.
I'm afraid your work is not done yet.
Mr and Mrs O'Connell.
I'd like to introduce you to a friend of mine.
General Yang.
Roger!
Well. he is the man who financed Alex's dig.
We're in this together.
Cheek by jowl. General.
Search him.
No. The Eye belongs to the Chinese people.
You can't do this.
So. Rog. you snake. how much did...
Is it Yin and Yang? ...pay you?
Enough to pull strings at the Foreign Office.
make sure that it was you two
who delivered the Eye. Turn around.
The Eye contains the elixir
from the Pool of Eternal Life.
I need you to open it. Mrs O'Connell.
No.
You're going to use it to wake the Emperor.
aren't you?
And his Terracotta Army.
At least. that's the general idea.
Raising an army of mummies is insane.
Listen. Yang...
(GRUNTING)
Easy! Go easy.
Time to open the sarcophagus. Move!
Read the inscription! Now!
Ancient Chinese isn't my forte.
Here's some encouragement. Wilson!
I'll do it!
No. Evy. don't do it!
They're just gonna kill me. anyway.
The inscription says
that only a drop of blood
from a person of pure heart
can open the Eye.
Your husband was right.
No!
Only the pure of heart would sacrifice
themselves for the one they love.
Open it.
You never called after our last date.
I don't have time for games. Alex.
You know my name. but I don't know yours.
It's Lin.
You want to explain to me
why you tried to kill me?
We could do that.
Or we could save your parents.
Wilson. you son of a bitch!
(GRUNTING)
- Get on with it. O'Connell.
- All right.
(COUGHS)
Once this touches him.
the Emperor will rise to rule again.
Finish him off.
(GUN COCKING)
(GRUNTING)
Alex. please! Don't. That's...
Don't. don't. Don't. please.
No. don't. Alex. it's me. Please.
It's not him. This is a eunuch! It's a decoy!
Where the hell's the Emperor?
(CLANGING)
Stay!
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Here we go again.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
I live to serve you. my Lord.
I can help you become immortal.
If you are lying. you will burn.
Wait! Wait! You wait for me!
I'm coming with you! Wait. wait...
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Watch out!
RICK: We got to put this mummy down fast!
The longer we wait. the stronger they get!
Open the gate! Open the gate!
(SHOUTING IN MANDARIN)
Yeah. yeah. yeah. I know. Sorry. pal.
There's a mummy on the loose.
- You wanna drive?
- Why not?
God. I love a woman who can drive a truck.
Hey. pal. I'm really sorry.
but you know what? Happy New Year!
Hit it. honey!
No! Move over!
What? No!
No!
(SCREAMS)
- What?
- Jonathan. get in the back!
Sorry about the Rolls!
You guys are like mummy magnets!
- We have to turn you around!
- Okay.
Excuse me.
- Hey. we could use this!
- Give me that!
- Oh. yeah. that's a better idea.
- RICK: Size counts!
Stop mucking about! They're getting away!
(GRUNTS) Just drive!
RICK: Aim for the Emperor!
JONATHAN: Aim for the Emperor?
- Light it up. Jonathan!
- I'm trying!
Fire!
(SCREAMS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Did we get him?
- Fire!
- What. again?
- Your ass is on fire!
- My ass?
- Hold still!
- Rick. my ass is on fire!
- Well. spank my...
- I'm putting it out!
- Put me out. Rick!
- Just hold still!
Spank my ass! Spank my ass!
All right. here I come!
LIN: Give me your hand!
Come on!
Watch out!
RICK: Evy. where are you going?
- Taking a short cut!
- Evy!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
- I told you it was a short cut!
- Right!
Now he's chasing us!
(YELPS)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Hurry!
Give me your hand.
Here. you're gonna need these.
- Don't wait up for me.
- Where are you going?
Out!
- Where's Rick?
- Where do you think?
Damn it!
You're mine!
(HORSES NEIGHING)
- Give me your hand and get on this horse!
- Get back. Dad!
Alexander Rupert O'Connell. you get
on the back of this horse this instant!
(EXCLAIMING)
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
Oh. God!
(SCREAMING)
JONATHAN: Evy!
We've got to go back and help Rick!
JONATHAN: Rick! Forget Rick!
Here they come!
I'll go after the Emperor.
Trust me. I've got a little more experience
with mummies.
And I have the only weapon
that can kill him.
Okay. I'll cover you. Let's go!
ALEX: Lin!
(SCREAMS)
- I thought you were dead!
- He missed.
(EXCLAIMING)
LIN: Look out!
(PANTING)
- Thanks. Rick. Could you get the cab?
- Does it look like I have a wallet?
You know. I would have killed the Emperor
if you two hadn't blown my cover.
I had everything under control.
Oh. yeah. that's exactly
what we were thinking.
Yeah. well. good going.
you raised another mummy.
And this bugger's got superpowers.
ALEX: He's got control over fire. water.
metal and who knows what else.
And you dug him up anyway.
Yeah. well. you're not gonna
pin this one on me. okay. Dad?
- RICK: Am I?
- Oh. stop it. you two.
No one's to blame here.
Wilson manipulated all of us.
Yeah. that's true.
I apologise for my parents.
But I thought we worked
really well together.
Except we failed.
I'm sorry.
we haven't been properly introduced.
- Who are you exactly?
- My name is Lin.
My family has watched
over the Emperor's tomb for centuries.
The Emperor cannot be killed unless
he is stabbed through the heart with this.
My mother put a curse on it long ago.
Mmm-hmm.
Well. a quick family meeting. Alex.
- Sit.
- Down.
What do you really know about this girl?
Well. not much. but after her help tonight.
I'm willing to go on a little faith.
- Faith.
- Time is running out.
You don't really believe in the concept
of personal space. do you?
If the Emperor reaches Shangri-La
and drinks from the Pool of Eternal Life.
he will raise his army
and no one will be safe.
Much as I'd like to stay
this boyishly handsome forever.
Shangri-La is a crock.
Yeah. but that's what you used to say
about mummies. too. Jon.
- You did pretty well off it.
- Good point.
The Gateway to Shangri-La lies in
a mountain pass high in the Himalayas.
Beyond it is a golden tower.
Once the diamond is placed at the top.
it will point the way to Shangri-La.
Yang still has the diamond.
and that's where
he and the Emperor will go.
She's right.
All the legends of the Eye
mention the Gateway.
I like her. Alex. She knows what's what.
Now. just say that we were to believe you.
could you guide us there?
Yes. I have been there once.
I remember the way.
Himalayas. We're going to need a plane.
Well. I know just the Mad Dog for the job.
MAGUIRE: Well. any self-respecting pilot
would land on the valley floor.
but I don't have any self-respect.
so I'll put you down
halfway up the mountain.
That should give us a good advantage.
MAGUIRE: Of course.
I can't guarantee any of us will live.
Great!
I'd tell you to fasten your seatbelts.
but I was too cheap to buy any!
(LAUGHING)
- Why am I laughing?
- Here we go!
RICK: Mad Dog. Mad Dog!
Ease up. ease up. ease up!
JONATHAN: Oh. God!
(SCREAMING)
JONATHAN: Maguire!
Come on. man!
Mad Dog!
(YAK BELLOWING)
RICK: Brake! No. no! Nobody move.
Nobody move. nobody move!
What is that God-awful smell?
The yak yakked.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Welcome to the modern world. my Lord.
Why did you raise me?
I love this land.
Only you can lead us back to greatness.
What is in it for you?
I want to serve as your general.
The last general I trusted...
betrayed me.
I will not make that mistake.
I cannot escape this curse
until I am immortal...
General.
I understand. my Lord.
We need to find the Pool of Eternal Life.
This will point the way.
(ROARS)
(MAGUIRE SINGING)
Can't you see it's Mr McGuire
come to court your sister Kate
You know very well he owns the farm
a wee bit out: : :
(PLANE ENGINE HUMMING)
MAGUIRE O VER RADIO: Delta-Tango-Alpha
to Ricochet: Come in. Ricochet:
Delta-Tango-Alpha. this is Ricochet.
Go ahead. Mad Dog.
Yeah. you know that Yang fellow
you told me to keep me eye out for?
He's just shown up:
Ricochet out. Thanks. Mad Dog.
That's us. people! Let's go!
- Jonathan. wake up!
- What...
Hold the line!
Good. we're a little more than halfway.
We're gonna...
We're gonna camp up there for the night.
ALEX: Lin says if we leave at first light.
we'll reach the Gateway by noon.
Did she happen to mention how she knows
so much about the Gateway?
No. not really. Kind of mysterious.
She's certainly managed to enchant you.
Come on. Alex. You obviously like her.
Mom. the thin mountain air.
clearly messing with your head.
Whatever secret she's hiding.
I just don't want to see you get hurt.
I appreciate that. but. you know.
I've had my fair share of experience
with the opposite sex.
Really?
How many experiences
are we talking about?
Well. you shouldn't ask questions you don't
want to know the answer to. okay. Mom?
Right.
Hey. Mom.
I'm sorry I blamed you guys
for raising the Emperor.
What's so funny?
My mother is under the impression
there's something between us.
I hope nothing romantic.
Yeah. well. I told her there
was no chance of that.
We're complete opposites.
you and me. right?
You guard tombs. I raid them.
You like ancient knives. I'm into guns.
Those are some
pretty insurmountable odds.
- Absolutely.
- Well. good.
Now that we've cleared that up.
we can focus on taking down the Emperor.
I agree totally.
Besides. you're not my type.
Of course not. You don't like a woman
who can knock you on your backside.
(CHUCKLES)
The expression is "kick my ass."
And for the record. you didn't.
Yeah. it's not easy being me. you know.
Then again. I don't suppose
it's easy being you.
is it. Geraldine. old girl?
If I'd met a girl like you. Geraldine...
You know. hard-working.
you don't say much.
you're a little bit hairy. but I don't mind that.
There it is! We found it!
The Gateway of Shangri-La!
JONATHAN: Go. girl! Go! You're free!
Go. Geraldine! Live free!
What did you do now? Rob an armoury?
Have you ever seen a Walther P38?
Looks pretty anaemic
compared to the Peacekeeper.
Well. it's not about size. Dad.
It's about stamina.
You want power?
I give you the Thompson submachine gun.
Fifty rounds a drum.
- Twenty-five a mag.
- Tommy's good. Dad.
but the cocking mechanism always jams.
Here. Check out the Russian PPS
Personal Assault Weapon.
Now. this is the future right here.
You know. it's experience that wins the day.
It's not all about firepower.
Boys! If I may...
Do we have a plan for the Emperor?
Yeah. We're gonna hit him
high. hard and fast
and smash him like a Ming vase.
- And if that doesn't work?
- We go to plan B.
Plan B! You go upstairs.
you blow up that gold tower thing.
- You light it up. We blow the guy sky high!
- Me?
- You! What?
- Dad?
So if the explosion doesn't kill us.
the avalanche will.
- You got a better idea?
- Yeah. I do.
I say we ambush him
with long-range rifles and silencers.
Long-range. that's a better idea.
Yeah. we can get in close. Dad.
- JONATHAN: Much better idea.
- And then we can finish him off
- with Lin's dagger.
- Look. I'm sorry.
I just don't put much faith
in your girlfriend's magic dagger.
- Okay. Dad. she is not my girlfriend.
- You say that now.
- but I still don't trust her.
- Well. I do.
- So you should trust my judgement. okay?
- Look. kid.
I've put down more mummies
in my time than you.
You put down one mummy. Dad.
Yeah. Same mummy twice!
EVELYN: Hand me the green wire.
will you. please?
Are you sure you know what you are doing?
Of course. I've done this a hundred times.
If the Emperor places the Eye up there.
all will be lost.
(PANTING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Clear a path to the Golden Tower.
Prove yourself to me.
(ORDERING TROOPS)
Let's give a warm O'Connell welcome!
(COMMANDING)
Fire!
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
(SCREAMING)
Bazooka!
RICK: Fall back!
Alex! Follow me!
(ORDERING IN MANDARIN)
We gotta take out those bazookas!
Go!
Fall back!
Move! Move! Move! Move!
Time to go to plan B! Blow up the tower!
Hey. I'm actually a little bit concerned
about plan B!
Couldn't we go straight to plan C?
Just make it go bang! I'll cover you!
Come on.
All right. let's go. go. go!
Come on. come on!
Come on. Oh. be good.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Set up a crossfire!
Move it!
(GUN CLICKING)
EVELYN: My last round!
(SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- Abominable snowmen?
- The Tibetans call them yeti!
(SNARLS)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Please! I need your help!
These soldiers are evil!
She speaks Yeti?
(YETI ROARS)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Shoot! Kill them!
Why do I always have to save the day?
I hate it when the kid's right!
(GRUNTING)
Get the other guy!
Thanks!
Trouble!
(SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
(GRUNTING)
You can die slow or you can die fast.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(GRUNTING)
Yes! Yes! Yes!
(LAUGHING TRIUMPHANTLY)
Yeah! I did it!
Oh. Mother. I did it!
Time for a retreat. I think.
I'm on your team! I'm a team player!
"One for all and all for me" kind of thing!
The dynamite. all this dynamite!
We should get out of here!
Back off! Back off!
LIN: Run!
(ROARING)
(GROANS) I hate mummies!
They never play fair!
Dad! Dad. what are you doing?
Over here! Over here! Come on! Over here!
Oh. no!
Rick!
(SCREAMING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Shangri-La.
That's a diamond.
I could use a diamond like that.
Dad!
(JONATHAN SCREAMS)
Okay. hold it. Hold on there. Dad.
All right. please. please. please
put pressure on it. okay. Dad?
RICK: It's all right. it's all right.
We've been in tougher scrapes than this.
Avalanche!
(EMPEROR ROARING)
(LIN GASPS)
- Help! Help me!
- Lin!
Please! Help me!
(SCREAMING)
(CRUNCHING)
(YETI GROWLING)
Yes!
(LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY)
I've got it! And I'm still alive!
ALEX: (MUFFLED) Help me. please.
Somebody help me!
- We're over here! Over here!
- Alex?
- ALEX: Mom. Mom. we're down here!
We're over here!
(ALEX PANTING)
Oh. God.
We've got to take him to Shangri-La now!
It's our only chance.
We made it!
The Pool.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Mother.
My sweet daughter.
I beg you...
My father is dying.
They are my friends.
Oh. please.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(RICK GASPS)
Thank you.
He must rest. We'll take him to my chamber.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Where are you going. General?
Our destiny awaits.
Well. it's not everyone that gets
their brother-in-law back from the dead.
Yeah. give me my four score years
and ten any day.
Is this Shangri-La?
I could live here. Lots of opportunity.
A casino.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
I was wrong to involve you in my revenge.
No. mother.
I would do anything for you.
ALEX: He's resting well. Thank you.
How'd you get involved in all this?
The Emperor murdered the only man
I ever loved. Lin's father.
I would have died. too. by his hand.
if the yeti had not found me
and brought me to this pool.
Hang on a second.
How did this all happen?
This was before Christ.
How long were you guarding his tomb?
Over 2.000 years.
The Emperor must never be
allowed to reach the Pool.
or he will have the power to raise his army.
And once he becomes immortal.
he can transform himself into
the most hideous creatures ever seen.
I will take the first watch at the entrance.
You know. I have no problem
dating an older woman.
I'm afraid we can't be together.
Wait. What? Why?
Because I'm going to live forever.
I don't want to watch you die.
So what? That's it?
You're just gonna sit
on the sidelines for eternity?
My mother has mourned
my father for centuries.
I don't know if my heart can bear it.
People can live an entire lifetime
in one look.
I watch my parents do it every day.
JONATHAN: Alex?
Your father's awake. Get up here!
Hello.
If this is heaven. it looks pretty good so far.
Nice to see some things never change.
Go easy on him. He feels terrible.
When I saw you lying there. Dad...
I've never been so scared in my life.
Well. that makes two of us.
I mean. you know.
you're not supposed to die. you know?
You're Ricochet O'Connell. right?
You get beat up. you get tossed around.
but. well. you're always standing there
in the end.
I never really thought of
the world without you.
Alex.
the truth is.
I'm just trying to...
I'm just...
I'm trying to be a good husband.
I'm trying to be a good parent.
And the truth is.
I've been dropping the ball lately. and...
No. you know. I haven't been
the world's greatest son. you know?
No. no. that's 'cause you get it
from her side of the family.
Come here.
My boys.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
You look tired. you should rest.
I'll stay.
Fate is about to deal its final hand.
If we are to defeat the Emperor...
I must ask for one more sacrifice.
Anything. mother.
Your immortality.
(EXPLOSION)
Oh. no! His powers have been fully restored!
Time to go.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
General Ming's daughter.
Your child will be mine.
He is immortal.
Hey! You three-headed shape-shifting
son of a bitch!
(LIN GRUNTING)
Lin!
LIN: Alex!
Alex!
He's taking her back to his tomb
to raise his army!
- Is there a faster way down from here?
- The yeti. They'll help.
But he's already in the air. It'll be too late!
Mad Dog can outfly a three-headed lizard
any day of the week! Let's go.
MAGUIRE: Portside! Nine o'clock!
Rick? Should I quit drinking?
O VER RADIO: Jonathan to Rick:
You'd better get a move on if
you're gonna beat him to the tomb!
RICK: Yeah. yeah. just get back here as fast
as you can with the reinforcements.
No sightseeing!
Here. Dad.
- Is that for me?
- Yeah.
Nice.
The Terracotta Army is not indestructible
until it crosses the Great Wall.
That's comforting. How exactly are we
supposed to fend them off?
When the Emperor built the Wall.
he buried his enemies underneath it
and cursed their souls
to hold it up for eternity.
Most of them were conquered soldiers.
I will call them to battle once again.
Unlock an altar. raise an army.
That sounds like a plan. Let's go.
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Grab her.
Guard her with your life.
Alex?
- Where'd he go?
- Where do you think?
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
AWAKE!
(HORSE NEIGHING)
Today you awake to a world...
in the grip of chaos and corruption.
Open the gates of the past
and free the souls
of the wrongfully damned.
I will restore order...
I will retake what is mine.
I will crush any idea of freedom.
In the name of the ancestors
and the righteous.
I sacrifice my immortality
and that of my daughter
so that you may rise this day!
I will slaughter without mercy.
I will conquer without compassion.
I will now lead you past the Great Wall.
Once you cross. you will be indestructible.
Bring down the wrath of the oppressed
on this Emperor and all who follow him!
I raised you for one purpose...
to enforce my will on the entire world!
Long live the Emperor!
I call upon the hundreds and the thousands
that you may rise up and seize this moment
to take your victory.
to take your justice
and to take your revenge!
Zi Yuan.
(SHOUTING)
It's General Ming!
Follow General Ming!
Prepare for battle!
These are...
They're good undead guys. right?
Oh. no. no. no!
Zi Yuan! Zi Yuan! Zi Yuan sent us!
- Darling. I don't think he speaks English.
- RICK: We're with Zi Yuan!
Zi Yuan?
Right.
Let's go.
To battle!
(GRUNTING)
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!
Archers form up!
Incoming!
- Hey! That's my favourite blue shirt.
- I've always hated that shirt.
(CHATTERING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Death to General Ming!
Charge!
Welcome to the 20th century!
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
We can't let them cross the wall!
(GRUNTING)
You are no longer immortal.
Honey! Fall back to higher ground!
I really hate mummies!
It seems the feeling's mutual!
Shut up. clay boy! Fore!
Run!
- Catch!
- Got it!
Next time I say. "We've been in tougher
scrapes than this." I mean this!
(GUN FIRING)
Die. you mummy bastards! Die!
There is no call for bad language!
Jonathan certainly knows
how to make an entrance!
Any regrets. darling?
None. Not ever.
- You okay?
- Yeah. sure. no problem.
We had it completely under control.
This guy ever run out of tricks?
No!
Mother! No!
Mother!
Mother! Mother!
Pierce through his heart.
You must live and fight on.
(CRYING)
She said through the heart.
Through the heart. Let's go.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Get in!
The O'Connells are going to
stop the Emperor!
So. Dad. what's the plan?
Divide and conquer!
No offence.
but isn't that a little short on detail?
- Twelve o'clock low!
- Hang on!
Remember our deal!
When this is over.
my men get to drink for free!
You can have the whole damn bar
for all I care!
I'm getting the hell out of China.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
I dug you up...
and I'm gonna put you down.
(SCREAMING)
Alex? Alex!
(GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Let go!
Never!
RICK: Enough tricks! Where's your honour?
Fight like a man!
(RICK GRUNTING)
Divide
and conquer.
(EMPEROR GROANING)
Now you can rule in hell.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
The Emperor is dead.
The Emperor is dead!
(SINGING)
- Evening. girls. You're looking well.
- WOMAN: Good evening. Mr Maguire.
- It's a fine night to be me.
- You dance great for an old lady.
Someone told me to stop living
on the sidelines.
- Well. he sounds like a smart guy.
- He is.
So I guess Dash and Scarlet
have their next adventure?
Why write about it when you can live it?
There's something incredibly romantic
about vanquishing the undead.
Even more romantic doing it with you.
- Kiss me.
- Don't have to ask me twice.
- Can I get your bag. sir?
- No. no. no.
Don't touch it. don't touch it.
Where are you off to. Mr Carnahan?
Someplace where they don't have mummies.
- Step on it! I've got a plane to catch.
- DRIVER: Yes. sir.
Yeah. Ciao. ciao. Shanghai.
Peru. here I come.
Soon after. mummies were found in Peru.
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm